+447 900267212

PROFILE

Chris-portfolio

Otutuchristopher97@gmail.com

Github

LinkedIn

CHRISTOPHE R OTUTU

Senior Mobile Developer based in Stoke-on-Trent, United Kingdom

Expert in Flutter mobile app development, I deliver robust solutions for iOS and Android platforms, emphasizing advanced state management, API integration, and intuitive UI/UX design

SKILLS & TOOLS

- Dart
- Flutter
- JavaScript / Typescript
- NodeJS
- Kotlin
- Spring Boot
- Mobile Application Development
- React Js

Architectures:

- Clean Architecture
- Bloc Architecture
- MVC & MVVM

State Management:

 Bloc, GetX, Provider & Riverpod

App Analytics:

• Smartlook, Appflyer

Remote Debugging Tool:

Crashlytics

Test Coverage:

SonarQube

Others:

- Git
- Fastlane /
- CI/CD
- AppCenter
- Flutter Platform (Web, IOS, Android)
- Firebase
- Jira

WORK EXPERIENCE

Flutter Developer

School Of Justice, Security and Sustain, Staffordshire University, Stoke-on-Trent, United Kingdom (3 Month Contract)

January 2024 – March 2024

- Led mobile development for the Catalyst Health Forensic Application which enable health care carry out both visual and forensic audit in Hospital Health Environment.
- Resolved app defects by reviewing bug reports and tracking repeatable malfunctions within software titles.
- Collaborate with team member in developing a react based admin web application.
- Collaborated with UI/UX team to improve product designs and ensure it aligns with user flow

Flutter Developer

Bird | 5 Isadora Lane, San Francisco, CA, United States (Remote Contract)

July 2023 - February 2024

- Led mobile development for the Bird application, enabling users to open a US checking account, build wealth, conduct cross-border and P2P transfers in multiple currencies, pay bills, and manage multiple accounts seamlessly.
- Implemented a streamlined checkout solution for both apps and websites.
- Resolved app defects by reviewing bug reports and tracking repeatable malfunctions within software titles

Flutter / Frontend Developer Parallel Score | United States (Remote)

January 2022 – June 2023

- Lead mobile projects within company from concept to architecture, design, implementation and development.
- Developed health care products that are based on FHIR Standard for data interoperability and with full support for Smart on Fhir to properly and effectively manage health record.
- Collaborated with UI/UX team to improve product designs and ensure it aligns with user flow by 90%+.

Microsoft Azure Board

APP LINKS

- Bird
- <u>EasyGo</u>
- OyaSync
- Lafia
- XPLOR
- BoxByBox
- RechargePro
- Etransit
- Brinmi Print

EDUCATION

Staffordshire University

MSc Computer Science (Software Engineering)

January 2023 - May 2024

Federal University of Petroleum

Resources

BSc Mathematics – 2nd Class Upper April 2014 – February 2018

- Setup CI/CD Pipelines using Azures Devops, Fastlane, Git actions, Firebase and AppCenter to automate product delivery.
- Converted old projects from MVP architecture to Clean architecture which helped in improving code quality, re-usability, maintainability, performance and test driven development and also using state management like GetX, Bloc and Provider.
- Wrote unit, widget and integrated tests for apps with Test Coverage of 80% and integrate with SonarQube for team validation.
- Resolved app defects by reviewing bug reports and tracking repeatable malfunctions within software titles.

Flutter Developer

Vertis Technology ltd | Abuja, Nigeria (Remote)

January 2021 – Febuary 2022

- Led the development of mobile applications for both iOS and Android platforms using Flutter, encompassing tasks such as testing, building, and deploying.
- Collaborated effectively in cross-functional agile teams, utilizing tools such as JIRA, Confluence, Figma, and Git for seamless project execution and communication.
- integrate RESTful APIs, alongside third-party libraries to enhancing the functionality of Flutter apps.
- Build intuitive features to improve the experience of users, across domains like payments, insurance and more.

Mobile Developer

Optisoft Technology | Lagos, Nigeria (Remote)

September 2020 – March 2022

- Team leader for five (5) mobile projects within the organization.
- Implement multi-lingual feature within application to improve user experience while using the application.
- Led the development of mobile applications for both iOS and Android platforms using Flutter, encompassing tasks such as testing, building, and deploying.
- Collaborated effectively in cross-functional agile teams, utilizing tools such as ClickUp, Figma, and Git for seamless project execution and communication.

Mobile Developer

FewerClicks Software | Madhya Pradesh 452001, India (Remote)

October 2020 – July 2021

- Implement multi-lingual feature within application to improve user experience while using the application.
- Led the development of mobile applications for both iOS and Android platforms using Flutter, encompassing tasks such as testing, building, and deploying.
- Collaborated effectively in cross-functional agile teams, utilizing tools such as Stack, Figma, and GitLab for seamless project execution and communication.
- Work with various team member to promote best practices and hold our mobile codebase to a high standard.